# William 'Joe' McErlane

joemcerlane@gmail.com ❖ # available on request ❖ Bay Area, CA

Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience, working in various fields from banking, Internet of Things, healthcare. I have a strong passion for learning and improving and rise to any challenge, be that new task or technology stack.

## **SKILLS**

Languages: Java, Golang, Python, PHP, Javascript, Typescript, C#, SQL

Platforms: Unix, Linux, Mac, Windows

**Architecture:** REST, SASS, BUS, ETL, AWS Lambda, MVC **Databases:** Mongo, Postgres, Oracle, Redis Netezza, DynamoDB

Misc: Docker, Ruby on Rails, Git, Nodejs, Bash, Unity

AI: Langchain, gemini

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Project Sanctuary Sept. 2024 – Present

Senior Software Engineer

SF, CA

- As part of a two person engineering team, I created user experience for Project Sanctuary members.
- Created static marketing sites using React hosted on cloudflare.
- User and event experience created on monolith and hosted on Digital Ocean.

## **Professionally Active Career Break**

Jul 2023 – Aug 2024

Self Student

SF, CA

- Delved into the world of AI completing courses in Gen AI by Google and Codepath
- Spent time traveling
- Rekindled my love of game development learning Unity Engine.

Lemonaid Health Aug 2021 – June 2023

Senior Software Engineer

Sunnyvale CA

- Developed GDPR pipeline to deliver client sensitive data upon request.
- Created medication bundle service to allow clients to purchase complementary medications as a bundle
- Designed and implemented generic integration of external clients (BetterHelp) to access mental health services via our platform

GetInsured Mar 2020 – Aug 2021

Senior Software Engineer

Sunnyvale CA

 Worked on a full stack app spending much of time breaking apart the JavaServer Pages monolith into micro services using Spring boot.

ElectricImp Oct 2018 – Dec 2019

Senior Software Engineer

Sunnyvale CA

- Worked within the web development team, primarily within backend creating the APIs on Nodejs and Typescript and MicroServices. Then expanding into a full stack position handling front end and back requirements.
- Creation of stand alone MicroServices such as, Auth and Search using Golang -Redesign and Rewrite of UI using Vue.js

End to End implementation of two factor hardware token to the FIDO2 specification

Dice Mar 2014 – Jul 2018

Senior Software Engineer

San Jose CA

- Developed API solutions for mobile, web and 3rd Party clients, in addition I tackle such problems as:
- User tracking using MongoDB scripting and data retention plan.
- Scalable data search using Apache SOLR
- Creating a Java Content Repository utilizing the Apache Oak Framework.
- Multithreaded Batch job implementation using Spring Thread Executor.

CitiBank Aug 2010 – Aug 2013

Software Engineer

Belfast UK

- Started Citi in a three-month training course covering capital markets, operating systems, programming, databases and ITIL.
- Based on my strengths I was hired as an Java Applications Developer in the Equities department
- I was assigned to the change the bank initiative to move from point to point communications to a bus architecture
- Implemented new Java middleware to send and message data via JMS using Queues and Topics Responsible for ETL which fed data to Netezza data warehouse
- Created reported solution using SAP Business Objects

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Ulster, UK

June, 2010

BEng Hons Computer Games Development

London/Derry, UK

- 1st Class Honors (4.0 GPA)
- Studied abroad at Dominican University
- Member of the Surf Team

### **ADDITIONAL**

Google Nov, 2024

Gen AI intensive course with Google

SF, CA

Week long course getting up to speed with gemini created by a team of Google's ML researchers and engineers.

CodePath May, 2023

AI/LLM bootcamp

SF, CA

• 6-Week course learning and utilizing LLM and rag to create a therapist chatbot to help others identify underlying emotions as a final project.